VAIBHAV SONI

+918955155073

vssonivaibhav6@gmail.com

vaibhavsoni.com

OBJECTIVE

I am a software professional with almost 2 years of professional experience in designing, developing and delivering software applications and products.

I have worked on a range of technologies from C++ application development to Node JS based web applications.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Feb 2017 - present

Apiria

Apiria is virtual assistant for modern age employees. A significant amount of productive time is spent by an employee on performing mundane and repetitive activity on a HR portal. Apiria is that 'smart' system which not only shows relevant information but also performs automated tasks to increase employee productivity.

- ✓ Worked on developing api-servers for supporting application's frontend
- Enhanced Testing by writing test cases in MochaJs and automating tasks using Grunt
- Designed and developed features which would help user to setup the application in various modes
- ✓ Designed and developed features like Expense Management System for the application
- Developed Frontend in Angularis for the various feature of the application

Aug 2016 – Feb 2017

Cantern

Cantern is an educational analytics company, they enable colleges to enhance their profile and students' employability through the power of data aggregate the data from various sources and employ a series of algorithms to understand and convert the raw data to useful insights for the college.

- Worked on developing product from scratch which includes Dashboard and different servers
- ✓ Worked On developing Reporting framework which include usages of Phantom Js, Nodejs, MongoDb, Expressjs
- ✓ Have Also worked on Charting and graph libraries like Morris js , Plottable js , C3js etc .
- ✓ Developed various in house tools to make download and modify reports

Oct 2015 – Aug 2016

EroNkan Technologies Private Limited,

Bangalore, India

Eronkan provides various IIOT services to enterprises. I have worked on the core product features and also internal tools. The technology stack that I was involved in consisted of Node JS and EmberJS.

- ✓ Responsible for maintaining beta version of the product on an ec2 instances which include updating source code, regularly test new features etc.
- ✓ Worked on building a monitoring system which keep check on driver's status installed on client's system.
- Worked on automation of server related task using monit, upstart and shell scripts.
- ✓ Worked on various customizations of frontend templates to fulfil client requirements.
- ✓ Worked on developing various api used for various features in the framework, developed using various tools like redis, rabbitmq, sqs etc.
- ✓ Worked on developing alerting systems which uses sms, mails to send alert to customers in case of various client defined situations.
- ✓ Have also made many clients visit where I was responsible to fetch data from FANUC CNC machine using RS232 ports.

SKILLS

JavaScript, Nodejs, AngularJs, Mochajs, HTML, CSS, PostgreSQL, Cassandra, Redis, Rabbitmq, Linux, AWS SQS, Monit, C, C++, JSP, ACE editor, Bootstrap, Processing, Knexjs, Server-Administration etc.

OTHER COURSES

- ✓ Introduction to Computational Arts (University Of New York Online).
- ✓ HTML5.1x: Web Design Fundamentals (Part 1) (Through edx.org by W3C)

INTERNSHIP/TRAINING

✓ Girnar Technologies Pvt ltd Jaipur .

WORKSHOPS & SEMINARS

- ✓ Ethical Hacking 1.0 & lab by i3indya Technologies at Neuron 12 MNIT Jaipur on 4th November 2012.
- ✓ NEN Entrepreneur Workshop Held at college campus.
- ✓ Attended Infosys Campus Connect workshops held at college

EDUCATION

2015	Bachelor of Technology (RTU) (Computer Science)
	Poornima Institute Of Engineering And Technology Jaipur, Rajasthan, India
2010	Higher Secondary Certificate(12 th) (CBSE)
	Army Public School, Bikaner, Rajasthan, India
2008	Secondary School Certificate (10 th) (CBSE)
	Army Public School, Bikaner, Rajasthan, India

I hereby declare that all the information mentioned above is true to the best of my knowledge.

Vaibhav Soni